what's up guys this is Nick at
bobbrand.com and today we get a really
exciting video talking about the best
protein bars on the market because we
live in a year where we have made
protein bars that actually tastes like
muffins and brownies and rice krispie
treats we no longer have to have protein
bars that taste like chalk and are not
fine at all to eat it's a really
exciting industry at the moment and
probably was just in general uh really
good if you want to will obviously
increase your protein intake make it a
bit easier but also if you want to
manage your blood sugar a little more
easily by avoiding fast digesting
carbohydrates or if you have trouble
managing your appetite as well because
protein is really really filling and
that was just convenient when you're on
the go like protein is the hardest
macronutrient to get when you're out and
about on the go and it's the most
expensive even though a protein is like
the most important macronutrient right
like can we say that it's like a very
important macronutrient the body is
pretty much always happy to get some
extra protein right so here we're
talking about the best protein bars
we're going to talk about the best
crunchy ones the best all-natural ones
the best meat based ones and more so
make sure you keep watching before we
jump into the benefits of eating protein
bars and the full list I shouldn't
emphasize here I'm not a doctor or a
medical professional so if you are
looking to make any big dramatic changes
or even little changes to your
supplement regimen or your nutrition
intake make sure you speak to a doctor a
dietitian or a medical professional
first to get it qualified from you you
know what before I go any further I'm
just going to tell you what my favorite
protein bar is on the Monaco right it's
this one transparent Labs uncut we think
this is the best protein bar you can get
it's going to sell them and approach
with 16 grams of protein what they do is
a two to one to one ratio of carbs to
Fat to protein which means it's a really
good idea if you are someone who leads
an active lifestyle or is not on like a
keto or low carb diet because you know
carbohydrates are actually very
important to get in your diet but it
doesn't have too many it's nice two to
one to one ratio and the ingredients are
totally all natural they're no
artificial flavors or sweetness here
which are really common in these which
doesn't say anything wrong with that but
if you're someone who likes to limit
them this is a very good and very tasty
option because a lot of the flavor comes
from honey and almonds and natural
ingredients like that so this is a
really good taste
so what are the benefits of getting
protein bars I mean look whether you are
looking to build a bit of muscle or lose
a bit of fat or both
increasing your protein intake is likely
a good strategy to go about most sports
nutritionists they'll recommend like 0.7
to 1 gram of protein per pound of body
weight and higher protein diets like
that not only do they have links to
again like better body composition like
more favorable ratios of muscle to body
fat they also have links to better
controlled appetite as well like it's
going to be easier to stick to certain
diets you're going to be Fuller for
longer it can also help to manage blood
sugar in that respect because they
absorb fairly slowly relative to like a
candy bar or something this is going to
be much more better for stable blood
sugar levels in addition to that higher
protein diets have very strong links to
like really strong bones and healthier
blood pressure levels as well so it's
not just an aesthetic Endeavor higher
protein diets have a wide range of other
healthful effects Beyond just the way
that you look in addition to that it's
just really convenient like a bar is a
more convenient way to get your protein
than even protein powder which is
already very convenient and expensive as
a means to do it even when I am making
all our own food myself and I'm not
going out and I don't need that
convenience and portability of a protein
bar I still try and wipe protein bars
into my daily diet just because they're
really tasty and they're usually a
pretty good source of fiber as well so
our favorite project bar is transparent
Labs uncut there's lots to like about
this but it's really good for as I
mentioned earlier people who are active
and athletes it's not ideal for people
who are following really low carb diets
or really low calorie diets but for like
the average person's diet or for an
athlete these are really good way to
provide some sustained energy and also
to curb appetite and as well as
providing like some nice nutrients for
Recovery as well the 290 calories per
bar roughly and it's got that two to one
to one ratio I mentioned roughly
speaking of carbs to protein to Fat
which is a race that a lot of athletes
follow in their overall diet plans as
well so it can fit really neatly into a
variety of plants and as I mentioned
it's also got no artificial flavors or
sweetness or anything the flavor largely
comes from like honey and roasted
almonds there's also whey protein
isolate and chocolate chips in here as
well it was a very all-natural product
and surprisingly we also made this the
best protein bar for the money when you
get a box of these it winds up at
roughly 2.50 per bar and I encourage you
to go out and have a look at your local
Bodega or corner store or even
supermarket and compare the price of
getting an individual protein bar there
you'll find this is actually a pretty
decent value so in addition to it being
like pretty hard to find protein when
you're out and about it is as I
mentioned pretty much always the most
expensive macronutrient as well and it
can be a bit stressful but eventually
and financially getting enough protein
throughout your day if you're following
a higher protein diet so transparent
Labs uncut helps to alleviate some of
that stress and you know helps you to
get a bit more cut as well next up we've
got the little bar here from on it and
this is a very delicious butter took
home three Awards this year we are
awarding this the best tasting protein
bar the best way isolate protein bar and
the best for weight loss because as you
may notice it is on the smaller size so
it helps keep your calories and check a
little more easily now this is
absolutely delicious and it has all
natural flavorings as well one honor has
managed to do here is make a bar that is
really really delicious and does not
have artificial sweeteners and is not
very high in sugar so that's really a
very considerable fit they've pulled off
here in addition to that we really like
about this as like the all-natural
approach is that believe it or not this
bar contains vegetables but it's not
gross what we're talking about here is a
blend of powdered fruit and vegetable
extract that they've thrown in here
that's a little bit like what you'll
find in green superfood powders so this
bag here it does indeed contain like
powdered spirulina and berries and that
sort of stuff for an extra hit of
antioxidants but you can't taste it so
even though it's all natural no
artificial sweeteners and it's low in
sugar and it continuous vegetables it
still tastes really good so that's why
we named this the best tasting
especially relative to what's actually
contained in this bar if someone is
loaded in a whole bunch of artificial
sweeteners it wouldn't be that
impressive of a fit what they've done
here is really very impressive and
because it is just 140 calories per bar
and it's so nice and small like this it
is definitely a really good option for
weightless as well weightless at the end
of the day is strictly about taking in
fewer calories than you burn so you find
out how many calories you burn in a day
consume less than that that is how
weightless happens because this is lower
in calories it can help you in that
journey in addition to that because it
has a decent amount of fiber and protein
and fat in it it should have to keep you
full as well so it's a nice impact on
satiety and on calorie intake as well
again we also named this the best way
isolate bar so this gets a little bit
complicated in terms of science but uh
in Dairy protein you typically get whey
and casein right there's the two types
of protein you can get from milk and
Whey is what usually goes into protein
powders usually now there's several
different types of whey in the market as
well there's a way concentrate away
hydrolysit whey eye slit eye slit is
very very very very low in carbohydrates
and fat relative to the more popular and
cheaper way concentrate that's what
you're looking for one way I slip
there's plenty have it in this bar from
on it and in addition to that it's
grass-fed whey protein isolate now this
is a bit of an interesting category
because a lot of people like grass-fed
Dairy because it's meant to be more
healthy right but the health effects are
limited to the fat like it has a more
favorable fatty acid profile when it's
grass-fed because this is way isolate
which has practically no fat the health
benefits aren't quite so much a thing
but grass-fed away Iceland is still
really cool because it means the cow is
happier right to set my time outside
I've got plenty of grass that sort of
thing I'm really big fan of it even when
it's like a practically fat free product
like this I always like it when it's
grass fed for the same reasons why I
like to get organic meat instead of
conventional meat it might not
technically be healthier not always but
it means the animal had a nice life and
that's a very nice bonus so best way I
slip up for me and for us here at
Barbarian is on its protein bar right
here and the best tasting and the best
weight loss number four everyone to the
best post-workout protein bar I didn't
want to quickly mention that I might be
throwing a lot of information out here
at you so if you want to get the written
version of this article you can go if
you're in Pace and we see some of the
studies we're citing that kind of stuff
there's a written component of this
video as well just to make things easy
so you just go to Google right in bar
Ben best protein bars and uh it'll come
right up next up we've got a really big
winner on our list to come a whole bunch
of awards and it very much deserves to
it is from Legion this one here is our
best post workout protein bar it is also
our best for muscle gain and the best
all-natural protein bar Legion as a
brand really doesn't use artificial
flavors and sweetness which is uh can a
bit surprising in the supplement game
that can be a risky route to take but
they've managed to make a really tasty
protein bug here with all natural
ingredients and what's even more
surprising about that is that it tastes
pretty good but it still has fewer carbs
fewer net carbohydrates than it does
protein so it's very high in protein as
well you get 20 grams of protein in here
which is the most on this list 20 grams
of protein is a really considerable
amount of protein and with the
carbohydrates it's 24 grams with a nice
9 grams of fiber just four total grams
of sugar you do get 12 grams of fat here
which helps with satiety and everything
as well so the calories are good and the
protein content is really good the
protein per calorie content is very good
for muscle gain which is why we need the
best protein bar for muscle gain
absolutely no artificial ingredients
either Legion is very well known for
that they're a really big winner in that
category I've been holding it upside
down this entire time legion pressure
bar they're very very tasty as well and
they're good for post workout because
again there's a decent amount of
carbohydrates here there's not a lot but
around here we're not really massive
fans they'll be low carbohydrate
approach if you are working out
regularly so you do want to make sure
you're getting carbohydrates to be
honest the average athlete usually gets
like a good one to one one to two one to
three ratio proteins are carbohydrates
so they're usually getting more carbs
than protein you are getting that here
the net carbohydrates is lower though
overall though it's a good amount of
calories and carbs and protein and fat
to refuel your body after a tough
workout or you know what maybe take one
before the workout as well now I've been
talking a lot about dairy-based protein
bars here which makes sense because like
whey is the most bioavailable protein on
the planet but that does not mean that
there are no good vegan options out
there the best vegan protein bar comes
from organ or gain proteins snack bar
we're a big fan of this one so this has
a nice 10 grams of protein per bar and
they come from rice and pea Blends as
well if you don't know this uh when
you're talking about amino acid profiles
a lot of the time vegan proteins tend to
be deficient in one or more of the
essential amino acids which means
they're not available in those same
amounts whereas like animal-based
proteins they're going to have all the
essential amino acids in roughly equal
amounts but if you combine some proteins
like rice and pea together then you get
a really nice complete amino acid
profile now there are like soy and
amaranth there are some vegan proteins
that are complete but I'm getting a bit
sidetracked here my point being that
this bar at just 150 calories per bar
get 10 grams of nice complete protein as
well and what's really interesting about
this even more than that is that all the
ingredients are certified organic which
is very unusual uh to manage that in a
protein bar so it is organic and it is
totally vegan and it is completely amino
acid profile and all those other reasons
why the surprisingly tasty protein bar
from all gain is the best vegan protein
bar up next we're going the opposite of
vegan protein bars keto protein bars
what is the best high fat keto or
protein bar it's named after me actually
mix
keto bars it's not enough for me but
that's what I tell people because like
we sound more famous and successful than
I actually am but next keto protein bar
we're a big fan of it here so the
calorie and macro breakdown here one bar
is 190 calories you're getting 10 grams
of fat there are 20 grams of protein
here but you're getting six grams of
fiber so that helps to keep the
carbohydrate the net carbohydrate count
down and you're getting 15 grams of
protein as well so actually when you've
got the net carbs to the protein there's
more protein than carbohydrates and a
nice 10 grams of fat so if you plug it
into your macro calculator you will find
a mixed protein bar is indeed very keto
friendly and the ingredients here they
are pretty all natural as well there's
no soy which a lot of people on keto
diets are avoiding the sweetness comes
off from Stevia as well or rather
stevial glycosides and you also got a
protein blend made from milk and
collagen so the collagen makes it not
even vegetarian because that comes from
Bones this is not at all a vegan protein
bar but nonetheless a lot of people do
like to get extra collagen in their
diets uh because it can help to be
maintain and improve the health of like
skin and nails and that sort of stuff
but what it kind of tends to produce
less collagen as it ages so yeah
collagen supplements are becoming
increasingly popular on the market today
this is giving you egg white protein
you're getting whey protein you're
getting collagen protein and a nice
amount of fat from coconut oil and Shea
and nuts as well very very tasty as well
this is Peanut chocolate and I totally
wouldn't recommend them if you want a
nice fatty bum of protein up next is one
that uh I'm actually very excited about
myself this is the best crunchy protein
bar I was very happy to learn that a lot
of people are searching for crunchy
protein bars online because it gave us a
great excuse to try out the marshmallow
crispy treats from Pro mix what's really
really cool about these is that they
look exactly like a like a puffed rice
and marshmallow snack because what it's
done is they have this way of processing
the way protein that makes it like kind
of crunchy and bubbly just like just
like rice puffs like the breakfast
cereal right so what you wind up with is
a bar that's totally covered in protein
because it's always but it's really
crunchy like a children's treat and the
ingredients list and then macros are
really impressive as well like the
ingredients list like there's a lot of
really really natural ingredients like
coconut oil and vanilla extract and egg
whites and inulin from Jerusalem
artichoke that's a Prebiotic fiber with
a potential digestive benefits so like
the ingredients list is really really
legit and the macros are as well so one
bar is delicious and decadent as they
taste is 150 calories you're getting 15
grams of protein you're getting 13 grams
of net carbohydrates and just three and
a half grams of fat in this one and it
comes in a few other flavors as well so
then macros are going to vary ever so
slightly but you've got a snickerdoodle
flavor you've got more chocolatey
flavors this one here is the vanilla
crisp flavor and I'm absolutely insanely
crazy about it and I can't believe how
low in fat it is it really is a very
very impressive feet that pulled off
here the best crunchy protein bar next
up we've got a very interesting addition
this one is the best low carb protein
Buzz now it is through the Nyx is pretty
low carbohydrate these are unbelievably
low carbide hydrate we're talking about
the Epic protein bars because these are
meat these are these are meat Buzz right
these kind of came about during the
Paleo craze about 10 years ago and
they've stuck around because they are
really tasty like this chicken one here
is maybe like Sriracha hot sauce uh the
beef one here is jalapeno and these bars
except for the pork one which has six
grams of carbs but the rest of them have
one gram of net carbohydrate per bar so
really low in carbohydrates lower than
Nicks to believe it or not and this also
makes them keto approved it's a decent
amount of fat in these two they hold 30
approved there's no GMOs and they're
thoroughly unique experience in the
protein bar marker because again these
are meat bars right so I find them
really tasty they're not like Jerky like
they're not like dry and stringy like
they're nice and moist but they're not
gross I really encourage you to try them
out epic protein bars if you want to
just get your animal protein not from
dairy but you want to get it from like
actual meat like kind of we always have
as humans always started you know
processing whey protein powder right I
got nothing against whey protein powder
but these have a very useful and
important spot in the market the really
really tasty they have a variety of
flavors one gram net carbohydrates as
well lastly we've got a lot of questions
about the best protein bar for people
with diabetes now before going on I
should make it clear if you've got
someone with diabetes you should speak
to a doctor or certified diabetes
educator before making big changes to
your diet what's interesting about
extend nutritionist protein bar is
designed specifically for diabetes and
pre-diabetes Management in mind right so
the whole goal with this bar is to help
to keep stable blood sugar levels and
the carbohydrates the way they approach
it is really interesting here right so
the first thing you might see on this
label is nine grams of protein 25 grams
of carbohydrates right which might make
you pause but you take away seven grams
of fiber from the carbohydrate count to
get down to the net carbohydrates after
that nine grams of sugar alcohols which
is the way they keep it sweet but sugar
alcohols don't absorb the way that
sugars do so they often not counted in
people's carbohydrate counts and then
after that that it's got eight grams of
what they call other carbs and the other
carbs here are uncooked cornstarch and
glycerin and these forms of
carbohydrates they convert very slowly
so they have a minimal impact on blood
sugar so the way that this company has
approached the carbohydrate count is to
say that you get 25 grams of carbs take
away the seven grams of fiber the sugar
alcohol and the other carbs and just one
gram of net carbohydrates now that
approach is probably something you
should talk to your certified diabetes
educator about nonetheless the approach
to carbohydrates here is really
interesting because they managed to make
a robust and tasty bar especially with
the help of those sugar alcohols but the
amount of sugar actually impacting your
blood sugar is very very minimal so it's
really really interesting again speak to
doctor but this is a very interesting
approach that was designed specifically
for people with diabetes in mind and the
bar has a kind of very successful as a
result it's used very very widely so
definitely take a close look at extended
nutritions protein bars I've got a few
tasty flavors they've got a lemon one
and this one here is yogurt and Berry
and I gotta say this one's my favorite
so that about wraps up our list of the
best protein bars you might have noticed
we have a pretty wide spread of
different kinds of protein bars with
different ingredient profiles and
macronutrient profiles here for you and
that's because the right protein buff
for you it really depends on your
individual needs and wants and your
predispositions as well so like by that
I mean some people like they're cute
they're keto right they're really low
carb diets so they're going to want the
really low carbohydrate but other people
they might be vegetarian so even if they
are low carb they don't want to have an
all-meat bub they're okay with the dairy
but in addition to that like the
artificial and natural thing a lot of
people they prefer naturally flavored
products other people they prefer the
artificial stuff because it does tend to
taste better right that might be your
priority then there's what you digest
well because what's interesting is some
people have trouble digesting artificial
sweeteners like sucralose there's some
people that can like kind of mess with
their gut microbiome bacteria in their
gut sometimes but other people they have
trouble digesting the natural sweetness
like sugar alcohol for instance which we
mentioned and in the extend nutrition
bar here sugar alcohol is like a
reference Hall they don't really absorb
like the same way that regular sugar
does it's usually not counted in
carbohydrate counts so it can be really
good but because of the way they sort of
like ferment to the way they digest some
people have trouble digesting those so
they would rather have the uh the
natural sugars like just actual regular
sugar or they might rather have
artificial sweeteners the point here I'm
getting a bit complicated here but what
is really useful and helpful for one
person even like the fiber count can be
hard to digest for someone else so take
your own needs and your own personal
history into account when choosing a
protein bar and whichever one you do
land on we really do have a very good
spread here if I say so myself so
whatever your predisposition in your
diet is there's something here for you
so we hope you found this video
educational and useful and if you want
to see the full written version again
you want to get this information at your
own pace take a look at the ingredients
nutrition yourself you can just read the
full article by Googling bar band best
protein bus it does it stick around
we'll see you for the next video